Guide to the Records of the Office of the Chancellor (Elmer Ellsworth Brown) RG.3.0.4
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Chancellor (Elmer Ellsworth Brown)
1900-1937
New York University Archives
New York University. Office of the Chancellor
RG.3.0.4
47 Linear Feet
This collection represents the administrative papers of Elmer Ellsworth Brown, chancellor of New York University from 1911-1933.
Separated Material
Photographs and oversized materials have been removed from this collection.
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1861-1934, Papers
Records of the Henry Mitchell MacCracken Administration, 1884-1910
The Records of the Students' Army Training Corps, 1916-1921.
The Administrative Record Papers of University College of Arts and Science, Office of the Dean 1899-1941/Dean Archibald Lewis Bouton.
Arrangement
Series I and II are arranged alphabetically.
This collection is divided into 2 series:
I. Administrative Files
II. Miscellaneous Correspondence
Scope and Content Note
The Elmer Ellsworth Brown administrative papers measure 47 linear feet in 94 boxes and date from 1900 to 1937.
This collection includes the administrative records from the office of the president/chancellor, the highest administrative and academic office at New York University at the time. Chancellor Elmer Ellsworth Brown's term at NYU began in 1911 and ended in 1933, when he was name Chancellor Emeritus. Brown died in 1934.
Researchers interested in the growth and evolution of a metropolitan university will find a wealth of information in this collection. Subjects addressed in the collection include changes in the ideological and bureaucratic development of higher education in the 1910s and 1920s; the relationship of NYU to the city, community, and nation; and how the University handled anti-Semitism and racism.
Biographical/Historical Note
On November 9, 1911 Elmer Ellsworth Brown (1861-1934) became the seventh Chancellor of New York University. Chancellor Brown's predecessor, Henry Mitchell MacCracken ushered the University into the new century and laid the groundwork for the transformation of NYU from a small educational institution to a modern University. Brown's task upon assuming the role of Chancellor was to realize that transformation. He guided the University through an enormous growth in student enrollment, significant transformations in the structure of schools within the University, and challenges brought by the First World War and its effects on the city and economy.
Brown desired to establish the school as a legitimate university, distinct from other institutions in the city. In his inaugural speech, he stated, "We need a wider understanding and appreciation of the large purpose and the high responsibilities of this institution. But we need to have it more generally known in the City of New York that this is not the City College nor even a department of Columbia University." Additionally, he emphasized the public duty and responsibility of the University.
During the first decades of the century, NYU expanded both in terms of its academic offerings and physical space. By the end of Brown's tenure, NYU had outgrown the three floors in the Main Building, to occupy ten buildings around Washington Square. New academic buildings and athletic facilities expanded the Heights campus grew to 50 acres. Numerous colleges were organized under Brown, including Washington Square College, Graduate School of Business Administration, School of Retailing, College of Dentistry, School of Aeronautics, and the College of Fine Arts. Other divisions, notably the School of Education, were reorganized.
The over ten-fold growth in enrollment numbers delighted and worried Brown. That NYU had become one of the largest universities in terms of numbers in the country was encouraging, but Brown feared that the large number of students could overwhelm the school's resources and sacrifice the quality of education. Additionally, the University began to rely on student tuitions for income, as the meager endowment could not meet the needs of the growing University. A decrease in enrollment would pose a serious threat to university finances. America's entry into the First World War in 1917 had just that effect. Fewer students and a wartime economy strained the budget of the University. NYU's agreement to receive branches of the Student Army Training Corps at the University Heights campus and at the Medical College both fulfilled Brown's desire for the University to meet it public responsibility and helped to save the school from financial ruin.
"The development within the institution during the period of Chancellor Brown's administration gives to his work an influence and outstanding character in the history of the institution, and one which, in spite of the degree of expansion, has developed upon the lines true to the principles upon which the University was founded."
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection. Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted. Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Provenance
These materials were part of the New York University Historical Collection in the Gould Library at the University Heights campus. They came down to Washington Square with the closing of the uptown campus in 1973.
Social service.; Administrative records.; Universities and colleges |x Open admission.; Students -- Civil rights; Discrimination in education.; Universities and colleges |x Admission |x Law and legislation.; World War, 1914-1918; Greek letter societies.; United States. Army |x Recruiting, enlistment, etc. |y World War, 1914-1918.; Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); New York (N.Y.).; Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1852-1937; Withers, John William, b. 1868; Washington Square College; United States. Army. Students' Army Training Corps; Salvation Army of America; New York University. University College of Arts and Pure Science; New York University. Woman's Law Class; Bouton, Archibald Lewis, 1872-1941; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937; Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1861-1934; MacCracken, Henry Mitchell, 1840-1918; Madden, John T. (John Thomas); Boy Scouts of America; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; American National Red Cross; Snow, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1863-1957; New York University; New York University -- History -- 20th century
- Series I: Administrative Files
  Scope and Contents note
  The Administrative Files series consists of 78 boxes. Several folders relate to Brown's civic involvement and concern for philanthropy, culture, and social problems. See folders on the YW and YMCA, Volunteers of America, Salvation Army, the American Red Cross, Boy Scouts of America, the National Kindergarten Association, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and the Brooklyn Botanic Garden. Two folders address racial tensions: DuBois, W. E .B. and The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, a file which contains correspondence concerning discrimination at NYU. Materials regarding anti-Semitism at NYU and Columbia University can be found in Admissions, Selective, which contains reference to intelligence tests and how these were used (or assumed to be used) to discriminate against certain groups.
  For information about the relationship of NYU to government policy, see the numerous folders dealing with NYU's involvement in World War I, as well as the R.O.T.C. and League of Nations folders.
  Throughout Brown's tenure, he showed a genuine interest in student affairs. Many records reflect his personal concern for student clubs, fraternities/sororities, athletic events, etc. These files are inter-filed throughout the collection and are easily identified by titles.
  Few records address the role of women in the University. Also lacking is significant correspondence with other collegiate officials outside of NYU. Only folders on Charles Eliot, the President of Harvard and John H. MacCracken, President of Lafayette College contain substantial information.
  - Abbott, James (Chairman, Alumni Committee on the Million Dollar Fund, 1914-1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, Lyman (Editor, The Outlook), 1913-1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, James W., 1928, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Admissions: Entrance Requirements and Standards, 1911-1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Admissions, Selective, 1919-1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Advertising, University Wide, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advertising Club of New York, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Advisory Council on Americanization (U.S. Bureau of Education), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alexander, Dr. Charles (Regent, University of the State of New York), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alexander, George (President of the Council), 1919-1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alexander, George, 1924-1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alexander Hamilton Institute, 1918-1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Allan, Kenneth T. (Principle, Plainfield, NJ Junior-Senior High School), 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Allen, Beverly Sprague (Professor of English), 1917-1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alpha Mu Sigma Fraternity, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Altman Foundation, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alumni, 1901-1915, 1926, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Alumni Association of the Law School, 1912-1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alumni Associations, 1911-1919 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alumni Centennial Dinner (March 1, 1932), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Alumni Committee on the Million Dollar Fund, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alumni Day, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Electorate, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Extension Service, Intercollegiate, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alumni News (Alumnus), 1919-1921, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Relations, 1913-1918, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Scholarship, 1919-1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Secretary (Howard F. Langland, 1919-1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Secretary (Frederick M. Crossett), 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Survey, Committee on, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alumni, Prominent, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - America, University of, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1913-1915 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American Association for International Conciliation, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1916, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - American Book Company, 1913-1917 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1927, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Council on Education, 1920-1932 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - American Defense Society, Inc., 1917-1921 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - American Foundation, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Institute of the City of New York, 1913-1916 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Legion Award, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - American Peace Centenary Committee, 1912-1918 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - American Red Cross Society, 1914-1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - American Social Science Foundation, 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - American University Union in Europe, 1917-1931 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Yearbook Corporation, 1914-1931 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Amsterdam, University of, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Andiron Club of New York City, 1916-1922 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Andrews, Fannie Fern (Special Collaborator, U.S. Bureau of Education), 1918 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Applications for Positions, 1915-1919 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Applied Science, School of, 1912-1919 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Arnold, J. Loring (Professor of Electrical Engineering), 1914-1920 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Arnsdorf, Henry G. (Registrar), 1926-1933 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Arthur, James, Collection of Timepieces, 1926-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Artist Tenants of the University Building Washington Square, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ashley, Clarence (Dean, School of Law), 1910-1915, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1914-1933 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Association of American Universities, 1912-1915 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Association of Colleges and Preparatory Schools of the Middle States and Maryland, 1913-1920 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Association of Colleges in the State of New York, 1917-1918 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Association of Collegiate Alumnae, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Association of New York University, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Association of Urban Universities, 1915-1918 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Astor, Vincent, 1912-1923 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Athletic Constitutional Committee, 1926, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Athletic Control, Board of, 1926-1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Athletic Inquiry, Committee of, 1925-1927 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Athletic Inquiry, Faculty Subcommittee on, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Athletic Scholarships, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Athletics, 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Athletics, Council Committee on, 1930, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Athletics, Director of (Henry C., Hathaway), 1920-1927 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Athletics, Race Issue (University of Georgia Football Game), 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Athletics, Special Committee on, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Atkinson, Walter E. (Alumni Federation), 1926 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Auerback, Joseph S. (Council Associate), 1912-1933 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Autographs, 1914-1925 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Avram, Mois H. (Chairman, Engineering Fund Committee), 1915-1932 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Aymar, Francis, W. (Professor of Law and University Legal Counsel), 1918-1923 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Babcock, Charlotte (International Musical and Educational Agency), 1915 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Babcock, Earle B. (Professor of Romance Languages and Literature and Dean, Graduate School), 1915-1932 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Babcock, Kendric (U.S. Bureau of Education), 1912-1929 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Babst, Earl D. (President, The American Sugar Refining Company, 1915-1928 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bacon, Cleveland F. (Professor of Law), 1925-1927 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Badger, Philip O. (Assistant to Chancellor and Chairman, Board of Athletic Control), 1921-1933 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bailey, Thomas P. (University of the South), 1916 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Baird, Henry Martyn, Memorial Fund, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Baird, Mrs. William S. (Grace), 1920 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Baker, George (benefactor), 1922-1931 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Baldwin, Emma V. (Brooklyn Public Library), 1919 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Balliet, Thomas M. (Dean, School of Pedagogy), 1913-1929 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Baltzly, Alexander (Assistant Dean, Washington Square College), 1927-1929 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Banks, Edgar J., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Barber Associates Fundraising Campaign, 1918-1919 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Barlow, Joseph W. (Professor of Spanish), 1927-1932 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Barnes, Dr. Arthur (Colonial Secretary, Newfoundland), 1921, 1931-1933 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Barr, Jean B. (Assistant Registrar), 1916-1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bartlett, Alice Hunt (American Classical League), 1929-1932 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Battle, George Gordon (Chairman, New York State Sesquicentennial Committee), 1930 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Battle, Wallace A. (Field Secretary, The American Church Institute for Negroes), 1930 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bayer, Henry C. (Professor of French), 1921-1932 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Belgium Scholarship Committee, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Benedict, Charles S., 1918, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bennet, William S. (U.S. House of Representatives), 1915-1916 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Berg, Irving H. (Minister, Fort Washington Collegiate Church), 1927-1930 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Berkeley Oval Park (Bronx), 1922 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bewer, Julius A. (Union Theological Seminary), 1925 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bible Teachers Training School, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Biblical Seminary of New York, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bibliotheca Belgica Library, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Biggs, Dr. Herman (New York Academy of Medicine), 1915, 1920-1921 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Biggs, Dr. Herman, Memorial Fund, 1926-1932 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bill, Charles Alfred, 1922, 1927-1928 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Binder, Rudolph M. (Professor of Sociology), 1912-1930 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Black, Captain, R.D. (Corps of Engineers, U.S.A.), 1913 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1922-1923 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Bliss, Collins P. (Professor of Mechanical Engineering), 1912-1921 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Bliss, Collins P., 1922-1923 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Bliss, Collins P., 1924-1927 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bliss, Collins P., 1928-1933 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bloch, Joshua (New York Public Library), 1921-1930 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bloom, Major J.E. (S.A.T.C., Manhattan College), 1918 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Blunt, Lewis G., 1917-1920 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Board of Control of Student Activities (non-athletic), 1922-1926 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Board of Control of Student Activities, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Board of Control of Student Activities, 1928-1929 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Board of Control of Student Activities, 1930-1931 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Board of Control of Student Activities: Clippings, 1922-1928 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Board of Control of Student Activities: Minutes, 1926, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Board of Education of New York City, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Board of Estimate and Apportionment: Bellevue Hospital and Medical College, 1911-1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Bodman, Mrs. Edward C. (Ida) (Women's Advisory Committee), 1911-1913, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Book Stores, 1912-1914 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Borah, William E. (Chairman, U.S. Senate, Foreign Relations Committee, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bossange, E. Raymond (Dean, College of Fine Arts), 1926-1933 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bouton, Archibald L. (Professor of English and Dean, University College of Arts and Science), 1911-1916 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bouton, Archibald L., 1917-1921 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bouton, Archibald, L., 1922-1927 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Bouton, Archibald L., 1928-1933 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1914-1918 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Boyd, James (Member, University Council), 1913-1933 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Boynton, Nehemiah (Clinton Avenue Congregational Church), 1915-1916 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Briand, Aristide, Ceremony (President, Council of Ministers of the French Republic), 1921 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Brisco, Norris A. (Director, School of Retailing), 1920-1933 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bristol, Charles L. (Professor of Biology), 1913-1921 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Broadway Tabernacle Church: Men's League, 1915-1920 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Bronx, General, 1915-1918 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Botanical Garden, 1915, 1918, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Dr. Arthur J. (Chairman, Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church), 1916, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Carleton (Professor of English), 1927-1928 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Elmer E.: Biographical Material, 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Elmer E.: Clippings re Selection as Chancellor, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Brown, Elmer E.: Dinner for Student and University Officers, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Brown, Elmer E.: Inauguration as Chancellor and Educational Conference, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Brown, Elmer E.: Thanksgiving Day Letter, 1928, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Frederick (benefactor), 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Kate Collins: Bequest, 1921-1922 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Brown, Marshall S. (Acting Dean, University College and Dean of the Faculties), 1913-1920 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Marshall S., 1921-1922 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Marshall S., 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Marshall S., 1925-1926 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Marshall S., 1927-1928 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Marshall S., 1929-1933 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Marshall S.: Committee on Research and Publication, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Samuel A. (Dean, University and Bellevue Hospital Medical College), 1914-1932 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Brownell, Fred G. (Managing Editor, NYU Alumnus), 1924-1925 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bruere, Henry (New York City Chamberlain), 1915 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Buck, Gertrude, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1911-1931 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bureau of Business Research, 1922-1929 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bureau of Business Research: Inquiry, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Bureau of Business Research: Inquiry, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of Business Research: Inquiry, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Bureau of Business Research: Printed Material, 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Business Research: Printed Material, 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Business Fellowships, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Business School, Graduate, 1924, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Busse, Alvin C. (Bureau of Public Information), 1930-1933 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Butler, Emily O., 1917-1927 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Butler, William Allen, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Butler Hall, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - California, University of, 1917-1930 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Campus Concert Course, 1918, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Capen, Dr. S.P. (Specialist in Higher Education, U.S. Bureau of Education), 1914-1915 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, 1911-1918 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie, Louise W. (Mrs. Andrew), 1912-1932 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1915-1929 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1915-1918, 1932-1933 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Foreign Fellowship for Junior Students, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1912-1917 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1918-1933 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching: Report on Athletics, 1928-1931 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Institution, 1924, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Carter, Lt. Col. A.H., 1918 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Carty, General John J. (NYU Council), 1922-1932 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Catskill Aqueduct Celebration Committee, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cattell, James McKeen (Professor, Columbia University), 1913-1916 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Centennial Charter Day Dinner (April 28, 1931) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Fund Material, 1925-1931 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Centennial History (T.F. Jones), 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Centennial: Morse and Draper Commemoration, 1930-1932 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Centennial: Telegrams and Letters of Congratulation, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Central Recording Office, 1915-1916 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Century Association, 1915-1918 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Chamber of Commerce New York City, 1912-1918, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Chaplains, 1911, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Charnwood, R. Hon. Lord (The Royal Society of Literature), 1918-1919 (Box 16, Folder 3)